<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech-Careers on Waiting it Out</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/tech-careers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech-Careers on Waiting it Out</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/tech-careers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I need to function</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/what-i-need-to-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/what-i-need-to-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was once a digital nomad, long before it was cool. This was in 2015, when I stumbled upon a paid project I was allowed to work on remotely. As soon as the contract was in place, I put my life in Boston on hold and book a one-way ticket to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once there, my daily routine went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wake up, get ready&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find a cafe, ask for wifi password, order coffee&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stay at cafe, work from laptop until I start getting dirty looks from the staff - typically around 2-3 hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Realize how much cool stuff there is around me, spend the rest of the day walking around and exploring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. I somehow managed to get around 6-8 hours of work done on most days. But everything outside of that was so chaotic that I&amp;rsquo;m surprised I got anything done at all. It was a constant struggle trying to find the right environment to do work from. On days when I had meetings, it was even more complicated because I needed to find a place that not only had decent wifi, but also where I could teleconference. Co-working spaces weren&amp;rsquo;t much of a thing yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t mind the gap</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/dont-mind-the-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/dont-mind-the-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken two major years-long gaps over the course of my career: once from January 2016 to October 2017 (~2 years), and another from October 2022 to the present (~3 years). I realized recently that, out of the last 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for only 5 of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On paper, this is not a great situation to be in. This could haunt me for the rest of my career, as any astute interviewer will notice these gaps and have questions - if not serious concerns - about the time off. The advice commonly given by recruiters is to inflate my experience, or to make the dubious claim that I was engaging in &amp;ldquo;freelancing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurship&amp;rdquo; during this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
