<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Waiting it Out</title>
    <link>https://example.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Waiting it Out</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What I need to function</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/what-i-need-to-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/what-i-need-to-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was once a digital nomad, long before it was cool. This was in 2015, when I stumbled upon a paid project I was allowed to work on remotely. As soon as the contract was in place, I put my life in Boston on hold and book a one-way ticket to Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once there, my daily routine went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wake up, get ready&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find a cafe, ask for wifi password, order coffee&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stay at cafe, work from laptop until I start getting dirty looks from the staff - typically around 2-3 hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Realize how much cool stuff there is around me, spend the rest of the day walking around and exploring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad. I somehow managed to get around 6-8 hours of work done on most days. But everything outside of that was so chaotic that I&amp;rsquo;m surprised I got anything done at all. It was a constant struggle trying to find the right environment to do work from. On days when I had meetings, it was even more complicated because I needed to find a place that not only had decent wifi, but also where I could teleconference. Co-working spaces weren&amp;rsquo;t much of a thing yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experience-Value Accounting</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/experience-value-accounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/experience-value-accounting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I once did a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@AccountingStuff&#34;&gt;deep-dive&lt;/a&gt; into double-entry bookkeeping and I was not expecting to become so fascinated by it. It turns out that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to account for far more than just physical and financial assets. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s possible - and often necessary - to account for the value of a company&amp;rsquo;s brand or intellectual property. But these are not concrete things, and there is no obvious way of determining their value. Still, accountants have managed to come up with some clever tricks for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wasting time</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/wasting-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/wasting-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I seem to have become pre-occupied with the topic of gap years. It&amp;rsquo;s something that I have a history of doing, and a topic for which I hold a lot of passion and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My latest gap has ballooned to nearly 3 years, in part because I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://ben-miller.github.io/post/the-case-for-giving-up-in-2025/&#34;&gt;given up&lt;/a&gt; on getting back into tech (for now, anyway). When asked what I have &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; with all this time, I don&amp;rsquo;t always know how to answer. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go into it with a plan, and looking back it involved a chaotic patchwork of short-term decisions, each making sense at the time. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to make sense of what I did, what I gained, and what mistakes I might have made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A taste of co-living</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/a-taste-of-coliving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/a-taste-of-coliving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a gap of nearly 3 years, I came to Oaxaca to have the time and space to get my career back together. A main reason for choosing Oaxaca was due to its abundance of co-working spaces. I am not a digital nomad - by definition, this requires income -, but I saw value in pretending to be one anyway. Fake it until you make it, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During my quest to find the ideal co-working space, I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://co404.com/oaxaca&#34;&gt;Co404&lt;/a&gt;, a so-called &amp;ldquo;co-living&amp;rdquo; space. After a brief tour of the miniature campus, I fell in love with it and signed up on the spot for my first month of accommodation. Two months later, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m stepping out of a time vortex. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m in a quiet private room outside of city center, I am finally in a position to reflect on my experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving up</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/giving-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/giving-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of evidence that the job market is fucked right now. The story of someone spending over a year searching for work, only to collect hundreds of rejections has become so commonplace that it&amp;rsquo;s not worth citing. Despite the &lt;a href=&#34;https://angelialevy.com/2011/08/06/lies-damn-lies-and-unemployment-numbers/&#34;&gt;comically misrepresented&lt;/a&gt; unemployment statistics published by the BLS, the &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lisep.org/tru&#34;&gt;unemployment rate&lt;/a&gt; is closer to 24%. In tech, it&amp;rsquo;s something like 200 applicants per posting right now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no saying when this will improve. Maybe next year, maybe in 5, maybe never. Either market conditions will improve, we&amp;rsquo;ll undergo some major (hopefully socialist) political shift, or things will continue to get worse. Either we&amp;rsquo;re doomed or we&amp;rsquo;re not. If we&amp;rsquo;re doomed, there&amp;rsquo;s not much that doubling down on your job search is going to do right now. If we&amp;rsquo;re not, then it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of waiting it out until conditions improve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t mind the gap</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/dont-mind-the-gap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/dont-mind-the-gap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken two major years-long gaps over the course of my career: once from January 2016 to October 2017 (~2 years), and another from October 2022 to the present (~3 years). I realized recently that, out of the last 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for only 5 of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On paper, this is not a great situation to be in. This could haunt me for the rest of my career, as any astute interviewer will notice these gaps and have questions - if not serious concerns - about the time off. The advice commonly given by recruiters is to inflate my experience, or to make the dubious claim that I was engaging in &amp;ldquo;freelancing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurship&amp;rdquo; during this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I structure my notes</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/bfo-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/bfo-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many, I suffer from the habit of digital hoarding. Whenever I come across an idea, future plan, or piece of useful information, I add it to my ever-growing system of notes, now exceeding 10,000. As this continues to grow, every few years I need to re-think how to structure my collection of notes to so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t collapse under the weight of itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through numerous phases with this. I&amp;rsquo;ve explored and/or migrated between various notetaking tools, including Evernote, Org Mode, Roam Research, Logseq, Notion and, currently, Obsidian. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a book on the Zettelkasten method, and have adopted a loose interpretation of the PARA system. Like many digital hoarders, tending to this &amp;ldquo;digital garden&amp;rdquo; has been an ongoing hobby of mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Formal Ontology</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/basic-formal-ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/basic-formal-ontology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back I became fascinated by the topic of ontology engineering and in particular &lt;a href=&#34;https://basic-formal-ontology.org/&#34;&gt;Basic Formal Ontology (BFO)&lt;/a&gt; and the work of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@BarrySmithOntology&#34;&gt;Barry Smith&lt;/a&gt;. Here I&amp;rsquo;ll make a basic attempt at describing what it is and why it&amp;rsquo;s imporant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An ontology, in a very oversimplified sense, is a shared vocabulary that allows for more precise communication between various people and groups. Certain words and concepts can be easily confused if we aren&amp;rsquo;t extremely precise in what we mean. Having a well-defined ontology or &amp;ldquo;controlled vocabulary&amp;rdquo; that we can use when describing some system, event, or entity helps us to get around this problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of repetition</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/the-value-of-repitition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 17:57:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/the-value-of-repitition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are countless ways of practicing meditation, and most involve fixing your attention on some physical or mental object and bringing your attention back to it, over and over again. In some sense, any way of engaging one&amp;rsquo;s attention - by mental or physical means - repetitively and over a sustained period can be considered a kind of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you meditate with enough duration and intensity, stuff starts to happen. You might find yourself in a deep, serene, or trancelike state of mind. You might find that it opens up a deep sense of effortlessness or intuition. The benefits can be profound.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be 34 in a few months. That&amp;rsquo;s old enough for a wide chasm to develop between you and the peers you grew up with, went to high school or university with, or worked at your first few jobs with. I&amp;rsquo;m browsing LinkedIn, stalking the people I used to know. People who I considered getting back into touch with personally, but who, if I reach out now during the job search I just started, might feel offended that I would only reach out as a matter of career necessity, rather than as a matter of friendship. I&amp;rsquo;m very impressed, even surprised, by what some of them have apparently done. It&amp;rsquo;s causing somewhat of a crisis for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>70-Percent</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/70-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/70-percent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read Atomic Habits, and I was intrigued by an experiment done by a photography teacher, where he split his students into 2 groups. One group would, at the end of the semester, be graded by the quality of a small set of photos produced. The other group would be graded on the quantity of photos produced, numbered in, say, the hundreds. By the end of the semester, it turned out that the Quantity group kicked the Quality group&amp;rsquo;s ass, not only in terms of quantity, but also in terms of quality. I found that story very intriguing, and it&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind how I might go about applying the principle in various ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
